James Schreiber

Mobile: +61 408 767 485

James.Schreiber93@gmail.com <u>ischrbr.github.io/portfolio/</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/techsmechs</u>

Summary

A Mechanical Engineer with 3 years experience of Process Engineering in the Aerospace/Defence Industry. A problem solver, driven by understanding the "in's and out's" of a process, then applying those lessons to new projects.

This approach increases autonomy and comprehensiveness when determining solutions, as well as providing context to a project strategy, selecting the appropriate tools to minimize efforts and cost during development. I.e (Rule 1: Pick the right tool for the job).

Experienced in developing, distributing and managing a variety of technical information, utilising a variety of soft and technical skills.

Constantly keeping updated with new technologies and taking on personal technical projects to broaden experiences.

A strong addition to any development team, and always learning. Recently, earned a Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate with Monash University, as well as Google's Professional Certificate in IT Automation with Python.

Every job can be broken into constraints, derived from goals and requirements. Refer back to these constraints when making informed decisions, and try to be a catalyst for that way of thinking in a team.

Technical Skills

Languages: Bash, C/C++, Python, JavaScript, TypesScript, HTML, CSS

Libraries/Frameworks: React, Redux, Angular, GraphQL, Sequelize, Mongoose, Firebase, Next.js

Design/Engineering: SolidWorks, PTC Creo, Fusion 360, OnShape, Altium, Eagle

Technical: Mechatronic Assembly, Troubleshooting, Tool Design.

SoftSkills: Technical Writing & Training, Customer Support

Projects

Twitter clone | Firebase, React.js, Redux and Material-UI | demo

URL: https://oopini.web.app/

Twitter clone built from a tutorial but refactored for async/await.

- Utilizes firebase authentication, functions, database and hosting.
- User, Post and Error data is dispatched through Redux.
- Material-UI used for styling. Server validated errors are handled with styling.

Second-opinion | ML5.js, P5.js and MaterializeCSS | git | demo

URL: https://github.com/jschrbr/second-opinion

A simple machine learning web application where the user can train a custom model based on visual likes and dislikes.

- Utilizes ML5.js to create custom like/dislike classifiers extracted from the MobileNet model.
- DOM manipulation through P5.js
- Styled using MaterializeCSS

PWA | TS, Firebase, React.js, Redux, Workbox and Material-UI | git | demo

URL: https://react-redux-pwa-129ae.web.app/

This project is an example of how to build a React PWA, using firebase as a backend. Redux is implemented with caching for offline use.

- Utilizes firebase authentication, functions, cloudstore and hosting.
- Maintains offline data by caching through Redux

Trakka TLX Searchlight New Product Introduction | whitepaper

URL: https://trakkasystems.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/TRK3837-TLX-Brochure-screen.pdf

Brought a new aerospace product from R&D to Production.

Leading the implementation of a flagship product from prototype to standard production within aerospace standards, within one year.

- Tested, developed and documented the assembly process
- Trained employee on technically advanced topics and procedures.
- Designed and implemented processes to maintain traceability of required testing and measurements through Production.

Roboteam Customer Support for the NZDF | website

URL: https://robo-team.com/

Providing technical support for a project with the NZDF EOD squadron.

- Learned to disassemble, maintain and reassemble several products and variants of advanced mechatronic systems within two months.
- Trained operators on basic maintenance and safe operation.

Simple-bin | MaterializeCSS, HTML, Javascript | git | demo

URL: https://github.com/jschrbr/simple-bin

Just a really simple dec. to bin. Calculator web app. Material styling using MaterializeCSS.

- Nice looking calculator, styled to intuit the user on how binary to decimal conversions work.
- Styled using MaterializeCSS

Work Experience

Trakka Tech - Technical Support Consultant

April 2020-Present, Melbourne.

- Leading the technical support for all RoboTeam products in Asia Pacific.
 - Supporting 100+ devices in the field.
 - o Offering troubleshooting and root cause analysis for system failures.
 - Implementing solutions, whether physical fixes, or communicating how devices should be operated.
- Spearheaded the development of Customer Support Management tool in ZOHO improving internal system quality
 - Deployed as a centralised database for open and closed issues.
 - Stores all relevant images and test results, allowing for a more thorough analysis of operating metrics.
 - Generates formatted reports for Management, based on the technicians log inputs during a job.

Trakka Systems - Process Improvement Manager and Production Engineer

Feb 2019 - Feb 2020, Melbourne

- Successfully implemented a new flagship product into an regulated production environment.
 - Achieved by implementing electronic work instructions to efficiently disseminate technical information, while easily managing updates and distribution.
 - o Authored hundreds of guides and work instructions using Dozuki software.
 - Created web apps to interface with Dozuki's API and create reports using existing or improved templates.
- Onboarded dozens of staff in highly demanding technical roles.

Trakka Systems - Process Engineer

Feb 2017 - Feb 2019. Melbourne

- Managed Production environment handling non-conformances and other issues that could affect on time delivery.
 - Maintaining existing documentation using Microsoft Office tools
 - Utilising existing SharePoint tools for managing non-conformances and issues

- Creating Work Instructions and other technical documents based on requirements specified on sharepoint
- Created python scripts for analysing Navision data that was not available natively.
- Implemented changes in existing documentation under a AS9100 certified Quality
 Management System using the Plan-Do-Check-Act lifecycle.
- Plentiful experience in hands-on assembly in Production and R&D environments.

Kevin Stahlmon - Apprentice

Aug 2014 - Dec 2016, Byron Bay

- Learned the basics of working with hand and power tools.
- Initial exposure to larger scale cross disciplinary projects.

Starseed Gardens - Technical Officer

Feb 2013 - Dec 2016, Byron Bay

• An opportunity to learn and expose myself to a variety of fields including agriculture, mechanical, electrical, plumbing and IT.

Education

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate, Monash University, Victoria (2020)

Bachelors of Mechanical Engineering, Griffith University, Gold Coast (2013-2017)

Certifications/Licenses

Google's Professional Certificate in IT Automation with Python - (2020)

Certified IPC Specialists under IPC-620 C - (re-certified 2019)